footters.com 2017-06-10

# Privacy | Footters

_We want to be transparent as to what we intend to do with the information that you will entrust to us or that we will know about you, not just because data protection laws require us to do so, but because we believe in being honest to our users. We really could not provide you the Footters Services in the way we do now, without that information. So we’re sorry, but if you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Information, you will not be able to create a profile and be part of the Footters community. This Privacy Information is about your data and how Footters will use it, please read it carefully and, as usual, please contact us if you have any questions._

In this Privacy Information we will tell you about:

  * Information that we receive from you when you interact with the Footters Services  
  * How we use and process the information that we receive
  * If and why Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties.

Please read this Privacy Information carefully. When you use the Footters Services or you submit information to or through them, you consent to the collection and processing of your information as described in this Privacy Information and you accept the terms of this Privacy Information and our Terms of Use.

_This is where our lawyers start shouting because they fear that you got bored by now and they want to draw your attention to something important. Let’s make them happy and please continue reading._ IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY PART OF THIS PRIVACY INFORMATION OR OUR TERMS OF USE, PLEASE DO NOT USE ANY OF THE FOTTERS SERVICES.

Whenever possible, we will provide you with advance written notice of our changes to this Privacy Information. We will not make retroactive changes that reduce your privacy rights unless we are legally required to do so. Your continued use of the Footters Services constitutes your acceptance of the amended Privacy Information. The amended Privacy Information supersedes all previous versions.

_We live in a world driven by data. We believe that our Footters Services result in significant improvements if we use the right type of information in the right way. But rest assured that we care about your data: if we don’t need to know something we won’t ask for that information about you or use it._

We collect various kinds of information that you provide to us as well as information we obtain from your use of the Footters Services. We call this information “ **Personal Information** ”, because it’s information relating to you and that can therefore identify you.

See some examples, to clarify. Personal Information includes:

  1. contact data: your name, your e-mail address, telephone number, residence address;
  2. demographic data: your gender and date of birth;
  3. certain data about your online activity, such as:
    1. technical information, including your browser type, service provider, IP address, operating system and webpages visited;
    2. information about what you’ve searched for and looked at while using the Footters Services;
    3. metadata, which means information related to items you made available through the Footters Services, such as the date, time or location that a shared photograph or video was taken or posted;
  4. data we collect from your using certain features of Footters Services, such as when you post content, reviews or comments, or when you use plug-ins like “Me gusta”, “Golazo”, “Paradón”, “Fair Play”, “Jugadón” o “Vaya regate”, or when you share content with the “Share” button; and
  5. information about your location and your mobile device, when you download and use the Footters app and have consented to location services. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services.

Whether we collect certain types of information and how we process it, depends on how you use and access the Footters Services. We collect information about you in the following ways:

  1. From you directly. For example, when you create your profile, when you contact us, when you post content on Footters or you use any Footters Services.
  2. If you connect with social media through the Footters Services.
  3. From business partners and service providers. Third parties that assist us with our business operations also collect information about you through the Footters Services and share it with us. For example, our vendors collect and share information with us to help us detect and prevent fraud.
  4. From Cookies, web beacons, server logs and other collection tools

We may use Personal Information for any of the following purposes:

  1. to provide the Footters Services to you;
  2. to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer to you;
  3. for customer service, security, to detect fraud or illegal activities, or for archival and backup purposes;
  4. to communicate with you;
  5. to better understand how users access and use the Footters Services;
  6. to develop new products and services and improve our existing products and services;
  7. to provide you with advertising and direct marketing that is more relevant to you; and
  8. to enforce our Terms of Use

_Footters is not in the business of sharing personal information with third parties. However, we will share it to be able to provide services and run Footters business. Here we tell you when and why we will share Personal Information with third parties:_

  1. **To perform services**. We may disclose Personal Information to third parties in order to perform services requested or functions initiated by users, such as when you use the Share button.
  2. **With third party service providers performing services on our behalf** , such as hosting and data analyses.
  3. **For legal purposes** , to enforce our rights, protect our property or protect the rights, property or safety of others, or as needed to support external auditing, compliance and corporate governance functions. We will disclose Personal Information as we deem necessary to respond to a subpoena, regulation, binding order of a data protection agency, legal process, governmental request or other legal or regulatory process. We may also share Personal Information as required to pursue available remedies or limit damages we may sustain.
  4. **In aggregated form**. We may share information with third parties, in an aggregated form – that is, in a statistical or summary form such that it won’t be possible to identify you from that aggregated data. 
  5. **Promotional communications**. At times we may send you promotional offers on behalf of third parties. In these cases, we will only share information in aggregated form to those third parties.
  6. **Business transfers and corporate changes**. We may transfer Personal Information in connection with a merger, sale, acquisition, transfer or change of ownership or control, of the whole Footters business or of some of its units or assets. We will notify you before your information is transferred or becomes subject to a different Privacy Information.

**With your consent**. Other than as set out above, we will ask for your consent before sharing personal information with third parties.

We retain information as long as it is necessary to provide Footters Services to you. We also retain Personal Information to comply with applicable law, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our Terms of Use, and other actions permitted by law. After it is no longer necessary for us to retain information, we dispose of it according to our data retention and deletion policies.

We maintain industry-standard technical and organizational measures against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access and against all other unlawful forms of processing. However, the security of information transmitted through the internet can never be guaranteed. We are not responsible for any interception or interruption of any communications through the internet or for changes to or losses of data. Users of the Footters Services are responsible for maintaining the security of any password, user ID or other form of authentication involved in obtaining access to password protected or secure areas of any of our digital services. In order to protect you and your data, we may suspend your use of any of the Footters Services, without notice, pending an investigation, if any breach of security is suspected. Access to and use of password protected and/or secure areas of any of the Footters Services are restricted to authorized users only. Unauthorized access to such areas is prohibited and may lead to criminal prosecution.

You may exercise your rights to access, rectify, cancel and oppose Footters processing of your Personal Information, under the terms provided for in the applicable legislation, at any time. This means that you may ask us what information we have about you, request that we update that information, tell us that you do not want us to use it for a specific purpose, or simply ask us to remove that information from our files.

In order to do so, please contact us, indicating the specific right you would like to exercise and providing a copy of your official identity card.

The Footters Services may contain links to third-party websites and services (“Third Party Services”) with which we have no affiliation. A link to any Third Party Service does not mean that we endorse it or the quality or accuracy of information presented on it. If you decide to visit a Third Party Service, you are subject to its Privacy Information and practices. We encourage you to carefully review the legal and privacy notices of all other digital services that you visit.

If you are below the age of 16 at the moment of creating your profile, we will ask for your parent or legal guardian to consent.

A cookie is a file downloaded on your device when accessing certain webpages or applications. Cookies contain information about your device, such as the User ID, the Operating System, user settings, browsing history and activities you conduct while using Footters Services. Cookies themselves do not allow Footters to identify you, but may be linked to Personal Information about you to allow Footters to recognize you every time that you access our page or application helping us improve the services we give you by for example: storing your password, tracking your navigation habits and customizing your user experience, analyzing technical and navigational information about the use of Footters Services.

If you want to learn more about Cookies and how they work, visit www.allaboutcookies.org

Footters uses the following cookies:

  1. A cookie named **io** , to reconnect yo your profile
  2. Cookies from **Google Analytics** , for web analysis.
